export const GEOGRAPHYA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The scale of the map expressed in statement form is",
A: "One centimeter on the map represents one quarter kilometer on the ground",
B: "One centimeter on the map represents half kilometer on the ground",
C: "One centimeter on the map represents one kilometer on the ground",
D: "One centimeter on the map represents two kilometer on the ground",
answer: "B. One centimeter on the map represents half kilometer on the ground",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The distance from MAMPONG to Kofiase by road is approximately",
A: "12km",
B: "6km",
C: "2½ km",
D: "1½km",
answer: "C. 2 ½ km",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following settlements is visible from Banko?",
A: "Kofiase",
B: "Sompa",
C: "Massa",
D: "Manso",
answer: "A. Kofiase",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. What is the dominant vegetation in the South-eastern part of the map?",
A: "Scrub",
B: "Montane",
C: "Forest",
D: "Savanna",
answer: "C. Forest",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The feature in the North-eastern part of the map is a",
A: "valley",
B: "Cone",
C: "ridge",
D: "knoll",
answer: "C. ridge",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The footpath from Asaasease to Manso passes through",
A: "Peak",
B: "B. footpath",
C: "Valley",
D: "pass",
answer: "D. pass",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. If the map is reduced to a quarter of its size, what would be the scale of the reduced map?",
A: "1:25,000",
B: "1:30,000",
C: "1:100,000",
D: "1:200,000",
answer: "D. 1:200,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The area liable to flooding could be found in the",
A: "North-eastern corner",
B: "South-western corner",
C: "North-western corner",
D: "South-eastern corner",
answer: "C. North-western corner",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The contour interval on the map is",
A: "50 metres",
B: "100 metres",
C: "150 metres",
D: "200 metres",
answer: "A. 50 metres",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. What is the direction of Sompa from Asumin?",
A: "South-west",
B: "South-east",
C: "North-east",
D: "North-west",
answer: "A. South-west",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The third planet from the sun in the solar system is",
A: "Pluto",
B: "Earth",
C: "Mercury",
D: "Venus",
answer: "B. Earth",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following is not proof that the earth is spherical in scale of shape?",
A: "Ship eclipse",
B: "Lunar eclipse",
C: "Ocean submergence",
D: "Circular horizon",
answer: "C. Ocean submergence",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. On which of the following dates is the sun vertically overhead at the Tropic ot’Cancer",
A: "December 22nd",
B: "June 21st",
C: "September 23rd",
D: "March 21st",
answer: "B. June 21st",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A Ghana Airways pilot landed on one airport and observed that the local time was 9:00 am when the Greenwich Meridian time was 1500 hours. On which of the following longitude was the airport where the pilot landed?",
A: "60oE",
B: "90oE",
C: "90oW",
D: "l50o W",
answer: "C. 90oW",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The part of the earth’s crust which is covered by ocean seas is",
A: "Atmosphere",
B: "Lithosphere",
C: "Hydrosphere",
D: "Troposphere",
answer: "C. Hydrosphere",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The formation of metamorphic rocks normally involves the change of other rocks through",
A: "Faulting",
B: "Solution",
C: "Folding",
D: "Heat",
answer: "D. Heat",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Sedimentary rocks are easily recognized in the field because they",
A: "Are volcanic in nature",
B: "Are darker in colour",
C: "Are acidic in nature",
D: "Are oxide in nature",
answer: "C. Are acidic in nature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following rocks is impermeable?",
A: "Sandstone",
B: "Clay",
C: "Limestone",
D: "Chalk",
answer: "B. Clay",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. In which of the following areas is mechanical weathering most likely to dominate?",
A: "Monsoon forest",
B: "Equatorial forest",
C: "Hot desert",
D: "Savanna",
answer: "C. Hot desert",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the Following landforms may occur when large scale horizontal earth movement and stresses are settled in the earth’s crust?",
A: "Block mountains",
B: "Residential mountains",
C: "Fold mountains",
D: "Volcanic",
answer: "C. Fold mountains",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Which of the following is a high cloud?",
A: "Nimbostratus",
B: "Stratus",
C: "Cirrocumulus",
D: "Altocumulus",
answer: "C. Cirrocumulus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A rock through which water cannot easily pass is termed",
A: "Permeable",
B: "Porous",
C: "Impermeable",
D: "Hydrated",
answer: "C. Impermeable",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Relief rainfall is most common",
A: "On windward slopes of mountains",
B: "At the beginning of the rainy season",
C: "On flat plains",
D: "In Mediterranean regions",
answer: "A. On windward slopes of mountains",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Weather means the condition of the atmosphere in a place at a particular time",
A: "As a forecast",
B: "For a given year",
C: "In the past 35 years",
D: "In the past 7 years",
answer: "A. As a forecast",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Humidity is the amount of",
A: "Cloud cover in the sky",
B: "Water vapour in the air",
C: "Moisture needed to cause condensation",
D: "Mist in the atmosphere",
answer: "B. Water vapour in the air",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Isobars on maps are usually shown in",
A: "Inches",
B: "Kilograms",
C: "Millibars",
D: "Centimeters",
answer: "C. Millibars",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The difference between the hottest and coldest months of a place is the",
A: "Mean annual temperature",
B: "Annual range of temperature",
C: "Mean monthly temperature",
D: "Duration of summer",
answer: "B. Annual range of temperature",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The feature represented as A is",
A: "Continental slope",
B: "Oceanic island",
C: "Oceanic plain",
D: "Continental edge",
answer: "B. Oceanic island",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The feature represented as B is",
A: "Continental slope",
B: "Continental ridge",
C: "Continental shelf",
D: "Continental edge",
answer: "C. Continental shelf",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Ahyrenal plain refers to",
A: "An inland drainage basin",
B: "The floodplain ofa big river",
C: "An extensive artesian basin",
D: "The floor of the deep ocean",
answer: "D. The floor of the deep ocean",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Equatorial forest is known for",
A: "Hardwoods",
B: "Esparto grass",
C: "Teak",
D: "Pure tree stands",
answer: "B. Esparto grass",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The A-horizon of a soil profile contains",
A: "Parent rock",
B: "Humus",
C: "Regolith",
D: "Colloids",
answer: "B. Humus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. “It has plenty grasses short scattered deep rooted deciduous trees” This best describes the",
A: "Equatorial forest",
B: "Savanna vegetation",
C: "Montane vegetation",
D: "Mangrove swamp forest",
answer: "B. Savanna vegetation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following rivers is found in North Africa?",
A: "R.Nile",
B: "R.Niger",
C: "R. Volta",
D: "R. Senegal",
answer: "A. R.Nile",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. When population grows at a rate that is faster than the available resources can sustain, it results in",
A: "Under population",
B: "Optimum population",
C: "Over population",
D: "Youth population",
answer: "C. Over population",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. “It involves low cost of maintenance, can carry bulky goods over distance and is cheapest mode of transportation”. Which mode of transport does this statement refer to?",
A: "Air transport",
B: "Ocean transport",
C: "River transport",
D: "Road transport",
answer: "B. Ocean transport",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The number of people per square kilometre in a place is referred to as population",
A: "Statistics",
B: "Growth rate",
C: "Density",
D: "Concentration",
answer: "C. Density",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following best describes the term conurbation?",
A: "A city which has more than one million people",
B: "The city centre",
C: "The industrial area of an urban centre",
D: "The coalescence of several urban settlements each maintaining their separate identities",
answer: "D. The coalescence of several urban settlements each maintaining their separate identities",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following is a secondary economic activity?",
A: "Cotton ginning",
B: "Crop cultivation",
C: "Coal mining",
D: "Lumbering",
answer: "C. Coal mining",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Industries which use more perishable raw materials should best be located near",
A: "The source of power",
B: "The source of labour",
C: "The source of raw material",
D: "High population density areas",
answer: "C. The source of raw material",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Consumer goods industries predominate in developing countries because of",
A: "Adequate capital",
B: "Availability of skilled manpower",
C: "Scarcity of raw materials",
D: "Low level of technology",
answer: "D. Low level of technology",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. An entreport is a port which handles",
A: "The imports and exports of other countries",
B: "The export of a country",
C: "The imports of a country",
D: "Consumer goods only",
answer: "A. The imports and exports of other countries",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The cultivation of grape fruits for wine in plantations is called",
A: "Aqua-culture",
B: "Viti-culture",
C: "Agriculture",
D: "Horticulture",
answer: "B. Viti-culture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The salinity of the seas at the months of the Amazon and the Mississippi rivers are because",
A: "These rivers are in the temperature regions",
B: "Large volumes of fresh water are discharged into the seas",
C: "Very little evaporation occurs on these seas",
D: "These seas have shallow continental shelve",
answer: "B. Large volumes of fresh water are discharged into the seas",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The most common method of mining gold in South Africa is the",
A: "Shaft method",
B: "Panning method",
C: "Audit method",
D: "Quarrying",
answer: "A. Shaft method",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. which of the following will make gold mining in South Africa unimportant?",
A: "Depletion of resources",
B: "Adequate capital",
C: "Adequate skilled labour",
D: "High demand",
answer: "A. Depletion of resources",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The method of mining petroleum is by",
A: "Open cast",
B: "Panning",
C: "Drilling",
D: "Quarrying",
answer: "C. Drilling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following is the fuel for nuclear power plant?",
A: "Coal",
B: "Uranium",
C: "Natural gas",
D: "Iron",
answer: "B. Uranium",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The treaty establishing ECOWAS was assigned on May 28,",
A: "1970",
B: "1974",
C: "1975",
D: "1977",
answer: "C. 1975",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The volume of trade among West African countries is low because of",
A: "Similarity of products",
B: "Difference in the level of technology",
C: "Good transport linkages",
D: "Use of common currency",
answer: "A. Similarity of products",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]